My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
If the organization learned that Shinichi and Conan are the same person
إن عرفت المنظمة أنّ شينتشي وكونان هما الشخص نفسه
everyone close to me would be in danger!
!سيقع جميع من حولي في خطر
Only Professor Agasa knows the truth!
البروفسور آغاسا وحده من يعرف الحقيقة
With my identity hidden, there's always only one truth!
!هويّتي مخفية، وهناك حقيقة واحدة دوماً
That was a good movie, huh, Conan-kun?
كان فيلماً ممتعاً، صحيح يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah!
أجل
I'm hungry, Dad.
أشعر بالجوع يا أبي
Oh, is it this late already?
تأخّر الوقت بالفعل
Let's eat somewhere.
لنأكل في مكانٍ ما
Then let's eat there!
!لنذهب هناك إذاً
Are you insane?!
!أأنت أحمق؟
It'd cost an arm and a leg to eat sushi in Ginza!
!سأضطر للدفع بأعضائي لآكل سوشي في غينزا
Thank you! Come again!
!شكراً جزيلاً! عاودوا الزيارة
Tonight's the night for drinking!
كان الساكي لذيذاً الليلة
Please take your medicine, sir.
تناول دواءك رجاءً سيّدي
Your heart might act up again if you don't.
وإلّا قد يتدهور قلبك مُجدداً
I know, I know! You sound like my wife!
!أعرف! لا تتكلم كزوجتي
It looks like he's the president of a company...
يبدو أنّه رئيس شركةٍ ما
Yeah, I've seen him before in some magazines...
أجل، رأيتُه قبلاً في مجلة
Oh, yeah! He's Mr. Okida, president of Bigwood!
!صحيح! إنّه رئيس بيغوود، أوكيدا
Bigwood? The software company?
بيغوود؟ شركة برامج الحاسوب؟
Today's contract sure was big!
كان عقد اليوم كبيراً
And it's all thanks to the software you gave me a year ago!
وهذا بفضل البرنامج الذي أعطيتني إيّاه قبل عام
I really must thank you!
عليّ شكرك حقاً
Wait!
!انتظروا
You dropped this!
أسقطت هذا
Thanks, little boy!
شكراً لك يا فتى
Tokito! Why the hell weren't you paying attention?!
!توكيتو! لمَ لم تنتبه؟
Sorry! I apologize, sir!
!آسف! أعتذر سيّدي
I have to thank you in some way. What would you like, little boy?
عليّ شكرك بشكلٍ ما، ما الذي تريده يا فتى؟
Pardon my rudeness, but aren't you Mr. Okida of Bigwood?
المعذرة، أنت السيّد أوكيدا رئيس بيغوود، صحيح؟
This is who I am!
!هذا أنا
Private investigator Mori Kogoro...
...المتحرّي الخاص موري كوغورو
Yes! We don't need anything in return;
أجل! لا نحتاج شيئاً بالمقابل
just let me know if you ever need my services!
فقط تواصل معي إن كنت بحاجة لأيّ خدمات
Certainly!
فهمت
Well, I must be going now.
سأغادر الآن
Take care!
!رافقتكم السلامة
A private investigator, huh?
مُتحرٍّ خاص؟
I'm going to drink like a fish tonight!
!حسنٌ، سأشرب حتى الثمالة الليلة
Okida
أوكيدا
Mori Detective Agency.
أجل، وكالة موري للتحرّي
Oh, Inspector Megure! Good morning!
مفتّش ميغوري! صباح الخير
Mr. Okida's dead?!
!مات الرئيس أوكيدا؟
So Inspector Megure saw your business card
رأى المفتّش ميغوري بطاقتك في جيب
in Mr. Okida's suit pocket and--
...معطف السيّد أوكيدا إذاً
Yeah, and then he called just to be safe.
أجل، واتّصل بي من باب الحيطة
Say, if the Inspector is there,
إن كان المفتّش هناك
does that mean someone killed him?
أيعني ذلك أنّ أحدهم قُتل؟
Sometimes the police investigate unnatural deaths too.
تحقق الشرطة أحياناً في حالات الموت غير الطبيعية
Mr. Okida was an important person, after all.
فقد كان السيّد أوكيدا شخصاً رفيع المقام
Wait, you were with Mr. Okida last night...
...لحظة، كنتَ مع السيّد أوكيدا البارحة
I'm Miura, his secretary!
أنا سكرتيره ميورا
Sir!
!سيّدي
It opened by itself!
!فُتح من تلقاء نفسه
How did you do that? That was amazing!
!كيف فعلتَ ذلك؟ كان مذهلاً
The computer checked my fingerprints and then opened the door.
تحقّق الحاسوب من بصماتي ثمّ فتح الباب
Computer?
الحاسوب؟
This is an ultramodern house;
هذا منزلٌ حديث التقنية
nearly everything inside it is controlled by computer.
كلّ ما فيه تقريباً تحت تحكم الحاسوب
It's cool in here!
المكان بارد هنا
The air conditioning is programmed to always keep the place
التبريد مُبرمج بحيث تبقى درجة حرارة المكان مريحة
at the most pleasant temperature 24 hours a day.
على مدى 24 ساعة
Oh, Mori-kun! Thanks for coming!
موري-كن! شكراً على قدومك
No problem!
أجل
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Sorry. I told them to stay home, but...
...آسف، أخبرتهما بالبقاء في البيت لكن
We saw Okida-san last night too!
رأينا أوكيدا-سان البارحة أيضاً
Inspector Megure. This is his secretary, Miura-san.
مفتّش ميغوري، هذا سكرتيره ميورا-سان
Thank you for coming.
شكراً على قدومك
Mr. Tokito here discovered the body.
كان السيّد توكيتو من اكتشف الجثّة
He came to pick up Mr. Okida at 8:00,
أتى ليقلّ السيّد أوكيدا عند الثامنة
but he never came out, so he grew suspicious and came inside,
لكنّه لم يخرج، فشكّ بحصول شيء ودخل
only to find him cold in his bed, with his pajamas still on.
ووجد جثّته الباردة على السرير بلباس النوم
What was the cause of death?
ما كان سبب الموت؟
We can't say for sure without a proper autopsy,
لا يمكننا الجزم دون تشريحٍ كامل
but it was probably a sudden death due to a heart attack.
لكنّه كان موتاً فجائياً لنوبة قلبية غالباً
A sudden death?!
!موت فجائي؟
According to his doctor, he's always had heart problems...
كانت مشاكله القلبية تلازمه وفقاً لطبيبه
On top of that, I'm told he drank a lot of alcohol last night.
وشرب كميةً كبيرة من الساكي البارحة علاوةً على ذلك
Yesterday was special, as he had gotten an important contract.
كان يوم الأمس مهماً بما أنّه حصل على عقدٍ مهم
His wife said no alcohol, but...
...أوصته زوجته بألّا يشرب خمراً، لكن
Where is his wife, anyway?
أين زوجته بالمناسبة؟
She left with their daughter on an overseas trip yesterday evening.
غادرت مع ابنتهما في رحلة خارج البلد مساء الأمس
Last night, he went to a number of buyers' clubs,
ذهب لعددٍ من أندية المُشترين البارحة
and when he came home, he was so drunk he couldn't walk.
وعندما عاد للبيت كان ثملاً بحيث لم يستطع المشي
So I took him to his bedroom and put him to bed.
فاصطحبته لغرفة النوم ووضعته على الفراش
The estimated time of death was around 2:00 a.m.
وقت الوفاة المقدّر كان قرابة الثانية بعد منتصف الليل
I'm asking just to be sure, but where were you then?
سأسأل من باب الحيطة، أين كنت في ذاك الوقت؟
I returned to my apartment after 1:00.
عُدت لشقّتي بعد الواحدة
At around 2:00 I bought dinner at a nearby convenience store.
واشتريتُ عشاءً عند الثانية من متجرٍ قريب
I dropped an egg at the register, so I'm sure the cashier can vouch for me.
أسقطتُ البيض عند المُحاسب، لذا لعلّه يمكن أن يشهد لي
How cute! It's a Himalayan!
يا لظرافته! إنّه هيمالاني
That's Aslan. It's the daughter's cat.
يُدعى أسلان، إنّه قطّ الابنة
He seems hungry. I'll go feed him.
يبدو جائعاً، سأذهب لإطعامه
Inspector. I'd like to see the body for myself.
حضرة المفتش، أريد تفقد الجثّة بنفسي
That's fine, but you two can't come in.
لا أمانع، لكن لا يمكنكما الدخول
I'd pass even if you told me to look!
سأمتنع حتى لو طلبت مني النظر
I see...
فهمت
No exterior injuries, and no sign of drugs?
لا إصابات خارجية، أو أيّ آثار لعقاقير
But why was he sweating so much?
لكن لمَ تعرّق لهذا الحد؟
Look how damp he is.
انظروا لهذا البلل
The sheet too!
الغطاء أيضاً
For someone who died while sweating, there's too much here!
يوجد عرقٌ كثير بالنسبة لشخصٍ مات بنوبة
When did you get in here?!
!متى دخلت؟
The AC in this house is computer-controlled
جهاز التبريد تحت تحكم الحاسوب في هذا المنزل
so that the temperature is always nice, right?
فتُعدّل الحرارة لتكون مناسبة دوماً، صحيح؟
So then why?
فلمَ إذاً؟
You were told to stay out!
!أخبرناك ألّا تقترب
Get out!
!اخرج
The flowers are wilted.
الأزهار ذبلت
The flower store receipt...
إيصال متجر الأزهار
It's from yesterday.
من الأمس
His wife probably bought them before leaving...
اشترتها زوجته قبل سفرها غالباً
It's been less than a day. Why are they so wilted?
مضى أقلّ من يوم، فلمَ ذبلت لهذا الحد؟
The chocolate melted into a lump...
...ذابت الشوكولاته وتكتّلت
Do you like cats, little boy?
أتحب القطط يا فتى؟
Yeah!
!أجل
Say, Mr. Okida liked Tokito-san, didn't he?
أخبرني، كان السيّد أوكيدا معجباً بـ توكيتو-سان، صحيح؟
He made him his driver even though he's young.
فقد جعله سائقه الشخصيّ مع صغر سنّه
No, he's actually a programmer.
كلا، إنّه مُبرمج في الواقع
He was originally a programmer for our company.
كان يعمل مُبرمجاً في الأصل في شركتنا
He and a friend started a software company two years ago,
،فتح مع صديقٍ له شركة برمجيات قبل عامين
but it didn't go so well...
...لكنها لم تنجح
As expected, he went bankrupt a year later.
وأفلس بعد عام كما هو مُتوقع
Six months ago, he apologized to Mr. Okida
عاد على ركبتيه مُعتذراً للرئيس قبل 6 أشهر
and begged for another job-- even if he was just a driver.
وتوسّل طالباً عملاً آخر، ولو مجرّد سائق
So then Mr. Okida made him his chauffeur?
عندها جعله الرئيس سائقه الشخصيّ؟
Yes. He was a kindhearted person, after all.
أجل، فقد كان رجلاً عطوفاً
Oh! I shouldn't be here!
!صحيح! يُفترض ألّا أكون هنا
I need to inform the company directors!
!عليّ العودة للشركة وإعلام المسؤولين
No. Mr. Okida didn't hire Tokito-san as a driver
كلا، لم يعيّن السيّد أوكيدا توكيتو-سان سائقاً له
because he was kindhearted!
من خير قلبه أبداً
He was making an example to the other employees!
بل كان يجعله مثالاً لبقية الموظّفين
If he really was a warm-hearted soul...
...إن كان عطوفاً حقاً
Tokito! Why the hell weren't you paying attention?!
!توكيتو! لمَ لم تكن تنتبه؟
...he wouldn't have yelled at him like that in public!
لم يكن ليصرخ عليه في العامة هكذا
Oh, Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Say, what did you and Tokito-san talk about?
أخبرني، ما الذي تحدثتِ بشأنه مع توكيتو-سان؟
You seemed to be having a good time!
بدوتما مُستمتعين
About Aslan.
عن أسلان
He said that long hair cats don't handle heat well,
قال أنّ القطط كثيرة الشعر لا تطيق الحرارة
so they need air-conditioned rooms to live!
فتحتاج غرفاً مُبردة للعيش
That must be tough!
ذلك شاق
So if it was hot enough in here to melt the chocolate,
مما يعني إن كانت الحرارة شديدةً ،بحيث ذابت الشوكولاته
that cat should've been affected.
فلا بدّ أن ذاك القط تأثر أيضاً
But from what I saw, it doesn't seem weakened at all!
لكن مما رأيتُه لم يكن هناك أي آثار عليه
I'm gonna go talk to Tokito-san too!
!سأذهب للكلام مع توكيتو-سان
I hear you're actually a programmer?
سمعتُ أنّك مبرمج في الواقع يا توكيتو-سان
I heard you set out on your own two years ago
سمعت أنك استقلت قبل عامين
and started a software company with your friend.
وفتحت شركة برمجيات مع صديقٍ لك
When I grow up, I wanna make computer games too!
!أريد برمجة ألعاب حاسوب عندما أكبر أيضاً
Is that so?
هكذا إذاً؟
But I make business software, not games.
لكنّي أصنع برامج أعمال وليس ألعاب
Running a company must be hard.
لا بدّ أن إدارة شركة أمرٌ صعب
You went bankrupt in just a year, right?
فقد أفلست بعد عام، صحيح؟
Everything went great at first,
كانت الأمور على خير ما يرام بدايةً
but then a certain man got in the way...
...لكن اعترض شخصٌ ما طريقنا
And then he drove my friend to suicide!
!ثمّ... دفع صديقي للانتحار
Would that certain man happen to be Mr. Okida?
أيمكن أنّ ذاك الشخص هو الرئيس أوكيدا؟
There are all kinds of things in the adult world.
تحصل مختلف الأمور في عالم البالغين
Forget what I just said.
انسَ ما قلتُه
There's no question that Tokito-san hated Mr. Okida enough to kill him.
لا شكّ أن توكيتو-سان كان حاقداً على الرئيس أوكيدا ما يكفي لقتله
He might've begged for another job to get revenge.
ربما توسّل للعودة للشركة كي يأخذ بثأره
If Mr. Okida's heart attack was intentionally caused by someone,
إن كانت نوبة الرئيس أوكيدا القلبية ،من تأثير شخص عمداً
Tokito-san would be the prime suspect.
فالمتّهم الأوّل هو توكيتو-سان
But how exactly could he have done it?!
لكن كيف نفّذ جريمته بالضبط؟
Computer intrusion?
اختراق حاسوب؟
Yeah.
أجل
It's possible for a home computer connected to a phone line
من الممكن لحاسوب منزليّ مربوط بخطّ هاتفي
to infiltrate another home's computer system
أن يخترق نظام حاسوب منزليّ آخر
and change its air conditioning program, right?
ويغير برمجة جهاز التبريد، صحيح؟
It's possible.
هذا ممكن
For someone well-versed in that field, that is.
لشخصٍ مُلم بالمجال تحديداً
Tokito-san is a first-rate programmer, so he's definitely well-versed.
توكيتو-سان مُبرمج من الطراز الأوّل فلا نقص في معرفته بالتأكيد
But simply raising the temperature couldn't kill him...
...لكن مجرد رفع درجة الحرارة لا يكفي لقتله
What is this?!
!ما هذا؟
Oh, I was eating ice cream earlier. I must've spilled some.
كنتُ آكل مثلجات قبل قليل، ربما سقطت مني
What a slob! Now I have to change my socks!
يا إلهي، يا لإهمالك! عليّ تغيير جواربي
Say, isn't it a little hot in here?
أليست هذه الغرفة حارة قليلاً؟
Crank up the AC!
ارفع درجة التبريد
No, this is just right!
كلا، هذه مناسبة
You're young so it might not affect you,
أنت صغير السنّ فقد لا تتأثر
but it's best not to make it too much cooler than it is outside.
لكن يُفضّل ألا تبرد الغرف نسبةً بالحرارة الخارجية
I once read an article about how someone had a heart attack
قرأتُ في مقالة عن إصابة شخص بنوبة قلبية
when they entered a coffee shop with the AC on too high.
عندما دخل مقهى بدرجة تبريد عالية
A heart attack?!
!نوبة قلبية؟
Probably because of the sudden drop in temperature.
ربما بسبب الانخفاض المفاجئ في الحرارة
That's it!
!هكذا إذاً
Tokito-san warmed the room up
رفع توكيتو-سان درجة حرارة الغرفة
and then suddenly cooled it down to cause a heart attack!
!ثمّ خفّضها فجأةً فسبّب نوبة قلبية
But it'll be hard to find proof.
لكن سيصعب إثبات ذلك
Maybe if the program was at that man's home,
ربما إن كان البرنامج في منزل ذاك الشخص
but I doubt he would actually hold on to it.
لكن أشكّ أنه يحتفظ به
Yeah, I'll go check for myself!
أجل، عليّ التحقق بنفسي
There's something I'd like you to make for me...
هناك ما أريد أن تصنعه لي يا بروفسور
Have an idea, do you?
لديك فكرة؟
Here's some juice.
هاك عصيراً
Thanks!
!شكراً
What a surprise!
فاجأتني فعلاً
Nobody's ever asked to come see my computer before!
لم يطلب أحد رؤية حاسوبي من قبل
Can I see it?
أيمكنني رؤيته قليلاً؟
Huh? What's this?
ماذا؟ ما هذا؟
What's this flake thing?
ما هذه الرقاقة؟
Is something wrong?
أهناك خطبٌ ما؟
No, it's nothing.
كلا، لا شيء
This computer's so cool! I wish I had one!
هذا الحاسوب رائعٌ جدّاً! أتمنى لو امتلكتُ واحداً
It might be too early for you to have one...
لا يزال باكراً عليك قليلاً
Since you're here, want to play some computer games?
أتريد لعب بعض ألعاب الحاسوب بما أنّك هنا؟
Isn't that your car?
أليست هذه سيّارتك؟
It's the company's, but its alarm is going off!
إنّها تخصّ الشركة، لكن جهاز إنذارها أُطلق
I'll be right back!
سأذهب للتفقد
Open up! No?
افتح! افتح! كلا؟
Who put this here?!
من وضع هذا هنا؟
Was it that kid?!
!أكان ذاك الفتى؟
No good! It's not here!
لا فائدة، لا بيانات هنا
I was playing poker with the computer!
كنتُ ألعب البوكر مع الحاسوب
I won with only one pair!
!فزتُ بزوجٍ واحد فحسب
Good job, Conan-kun!
أنتَ بارع يا كونان-كن
I'm overanalyzing things!
ربما أفرطتُ في التفكير
That was just someone's prank!
كان مقلباً من أحدهم وحسب
Oh! How did it go, Shinichi?
كيف جرى الأمر يا شينتشي؟
From your expression, I take it you didn't find the program?
أفترض أنّك لم تجد البرنامج من ملامحك
Nope.
كلا
The only thing I learned was how to play poker against a computer.
كلّ ما عرفته هو كيف أغلب الحاسوب في البوكر
I dunno what to do now...
...لا أدري ما العمل الآن
This is a cat hair.
شعرة قطّ
Oh yeah, I probably got it from Aslan this morning at Mr. Okida's house.
لعلّها علقت بي من أسلان في منزل الرئيس أوكيدا هذا الصباح
I had forgotten about him.
صحيح، نسيتُ أمره
Aslan is a long-haired cat, so he'd be affected if a room got too hot.
أسلان قطّ كثيف الشعر، فسيتأثر إن ارتفعت درجة حرارة الغرفة
I can't lay out a theory unless I solve this puzzle.
لن أستطيع التفكير بنظرية حتى أحلّ هذا اللغز
Wait! I changed my socks earlier!
!لحظة، غيّرتُ جواربي قبلاً
Which means this hair came from Tokito-san's apartment...
...ما يعني أنّ هذه الشعرة من شقّة توكيتو-سان
Now I see!
!فهمت
Which means that flake was--
...مما يعني أنّ تلك الرقاقة كانت
Megure here.
ميغوري معك
Good to hear you again, Inspector.
يسرّني سماع صوتك مجدّداً سيّدي المفتش
This is Kudo Shinichi.
أنا كودو شينتشي
Oh! Kudo-kun!
!كودو-كن
There's something I'd like you to investigate immediately
هناك أمرٌ عاجل أريدك أن تتحرى فيه
about Mr. Okida's sudden death.
بشأن موت الرئيس أوكيدا المُفاجئ
Mr. Tokito, the driver? Understood.
السائق السيّد توكيتو؟ فهمت
Take Conan-kun and Ran with you.
اصطحب كونان-كن وران معك رجاءً
I'm sure they'll come in handy.
سيفيدانك حتماً
Bye.
إلى اللقاء
Why do I have to use this to fake my own voice?
لمَ عليّ استعمال مغيّر الصوت لتزييف صوتي الحقيقي؟
Talk about pathetic...
...بائس
Good morning! Sorry for the early intrusion!
صباح الخير! نعتذر على إزعاجك في هذا الوقت الباكر
May we come in?
أيمكننا الدخول؟
Of course.
تفضّلوا
Computer infiltration?
اختراق حاسوب؟
This Kudo kid sure has a good imagination!
لذاك الشاب كودو مخيلة واسعة حقاً
But I didn't kill him.
لكنّي لست المجرم
I'd like to ask you about the day before yesterday one more time...
...أريد سؤالك مُجدداً عن يوم ما قبل الأمس
Two nights ago, you put Mr. Okida to bed and then immediately left, correct?
قبل ليلتين، وضعت السيّد أوكيدا في الفراش وغادرت من فورك، صحيح؟
That's right.
أجل
Are you sure you didn't do anything out of the ordinary?
أأنت متأكد أنّك لم تفعل شيئاً غريباً وقتها؟
Anything out of the ordinary?
شيء غريب؟
No, nothing...
كلا
That's odd.
هذا غريب
I'm almost certain you took his cat two days ago.
فأنا أكاد أكون متأكداً أنّك أخذت قطّه قبل يومين
I believe his name was...
...اسمه كان
...Aslan!
أسلان
Yes, Aslan.
صحيح، أسلان
And then yesterday you took Aslan back to the Okida home.
ثم أعدت أسلان بالأمس لمنزل أوكيدا
When Conan-kun came here yesterday, some cat hair got stuck to his feet!
علقت شعرة قطّ بقدم كونان-كن عندما أتى هنا البارحة
I must've picked it up when I held Aslan at Mr. Okida's house
لعلّها وصلت هنا عندما حملت أسلان في منزل الرئيس أوكيدا
and then it fell off here!
وعلقت بملابسي وقتها
But Tokito-san! There's cat litter here!
لكن توجد رقاقات سلّة فضلات قطط هنا يا توكيتو-سان
These are used in litter boxes, right, Ran-neechan?
تُستعمل هذه الرقاقات في سلال الفضلات، صحيح يا ران-نيتشان؟
Yeah, they stick to long hair cats especially easily,
،أجل، تلتصق بالقطط كثيفة الشعر تحديداً
and they fall all over the place when they walk around.
فتتساقط في كلّ مكان عندما تتجول
Look! Here's another one!
انظروا! توجد واحدة أخرى
You don't have a cat, do you?
لا تملك قطّاً يا توكيتو-سان، صحيح؟
There's no question that you took Aslan, is there?
لا شكّ بأنك أخذت أسلان الآن
Why did you take Aslan?!
!لمَ أخذت أسلان؟
Uhh--
...السبب
You did it because you knew something was going to happen
لأنّك كنت تعرف أنّ شيئاً سيحصل
at the Okida house that night!
!في منزل أوكيدا تلك الليلة
The entire house would become unusually warm
سيحترّ المنزل بأكمله بشكل غير طبيعي
and then suddenly cool down.
ثمّ يبرد فجأةً
You love animals, so you took Aslan with you
أخذت أسلان معك لكونك مُحباً للحيوانات
because he would be affected and possibly even die!
وخشيت أن يتأثر أو يموت حتّى
Am I right?!
ألستُ محقاً؟
You're actually a nice person, aren't you?
أنت شخص لطيف وصالح في الواقع يا توكيتو-سان، صحيح؟
But what you did was wrong!
!لكنّ ما فعلته كان خطأً
Computers were created to enrich people's lives
اُبتكرت الحواسيب لتسهيل حياة الناس
and make them happy, right?
وإعطائهم السعادة، أليس كذلك؟
Yet you used one to kill somebody!
!مع ذلك استعملته لقتل شخص
That computer's your friend, isn't it?!
!أليس ذلك الحاسوب صديقك؟
That means you've betrayed your own friend!
!ما يعني أنّك خنت صديقك
You're right, Conan-kun.
أصبت يا كونان-كن
I almost lost a dear friend
كدتُ أفقد شخصاً عزيزاً
and my pride as a programmer.
كما فخري كمُبرمج
My program's on this disk.
برنامجي على هذا القرص
To be honest, I didn't think this would kill him.
لم أتصوّر أن هذا سيقتله في الواقع
I was going to think up something else if it failed.
كنتُ سأفكر بطريقة أخرى لو فشل
Why did you keep something that incriminating?!
!لمَ احتفظت بدليل مُدين كهذا؟
Every program I write is like a child to me.
كلّ برنامج أكتبه بمثابة ابن لي
I couldn't bear to get rid of it...
...لم أستطع دفع نفسي على التخلّص منه
Conan-kun. Could you tell this Shinichi something for me?
كونان-كن، هلّا أوصلت شيئاً لشينتشي ذاك؟
I don't know in how many years it'll be, but when I start my next software company
لا أعرف بعد كم من الأعوام، لكن عندما ،أفتتح شركتي البرمجية التالية
I'd love to have him work for me!
أريده أن يعمل لي
You too, of course.
وأنت بالطبع
Right! I'll tell him!
أجل، سأخبره
Shinichi really beat me this time!
غلبني شينتشي هذه المرّة
For my student, he sure is meddling!
إنّه متطفل حقاً بالنسبة لتلميذي
Since when am I your student?
متى أصبحت تلميذك؟
Hey, Conan-kun.
أخبرني يا كونان-كن
Didn't you say you saw Shinichi at Professor Agasa's place yesterday?
قلتَ أنّك التقيت شينتشي بالأمس في منزل البروفسور آغاسا، صحيح؟
Yeah! And when I told him about Mr. Okida he instantly knew that it was a murder!
أجل، وعندما أخبرته بحادثة الرئيس أوكيدا عرف أنّها جريمة قتل فوراً
Shinichi sure is smart!
!شينتشي-نيتشان مذهل حقاً
That's not what I'm asking about!
!لم أسألك ذلك
Why didn't you tell me right away?!
!لمَ لم تخبرني فوراً؟
You know I'm worried about him!
!تعرف أنّي قلقةٌ عليه
Well, uh--
...أ-أنا
No, I--
...كـ-كلا، أنا
Fess up!
!اعترف
Get back here, Conan-kun!
!ارجع يا كونان-كن
Oh yes, the phone rang then...
صحيح، رنّ الهاتف وقتها
Yeah! Conan-kun answered it!
نعم، أجاب كونان-كن
Yeah! They said, "I'm Tatsumi's wife, of course!"
"أجل، قالت "أنا زوجة تاتسومي بالطبع
Which means she was still alive at that time?
ما يعني أنّها كانت حيّةً آنذاك
Tatsumi-sensei was with me; his alibi is airtight.
كان تاتسومي سينسي معي فحجّة غيابه كاملة
And besides, the hotel is ten kilometers from his home.
كما يبعد الفندق 10 كيلومترات عن منزله
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Alibi Testimony Murder Case."
جريمة قتل شهادة حجّة الغياب
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Cassette tape.
شريط كاسيت